autoexpress.co.uk 2018-03-07

# Privacy Policy - Dennis Publishing

Last updated October 2017

Your personal information is being processed by Dennis Publishing (UK) Ltd (“we”). We are committed to managing your personal information in accordance with current legislation and best practice. Our aim is to be responsible, relevant and secure when using your data. You can find out more about us by visiting [http://www.dennis.co.uk/about-us](http://www.dennis.co.uk/about-us).

We are owned and run for the benefit of the [Heart of England Forest](https://www.heartofenglandforest.com/); an exciting and ambitious charity aiming to plant and preserve the largest native broadleaf forest in England. Planting tomorrow’s great native woodland, with the help of everyone, open to anyone, one tree at a time and accordingly if you consent to receiving direct promotional materials from Dennis Publishing you will also be taken to have subscribed to receive promotional materials of the same type from the Heart of England Forest.

Whenever you provide personal information we will treat that information in accordance with this Notice. We endeavour at all times to keep your data accurate and secure, and to honour your data preferences with regard to receipt of direct marketing e.g. postal communications, email, mobile messaging and telephone calls.   
  
Dennis Publishing (UK) Ltd has a portfolio of over 30 brands which operate in four areas of excellence: Current Affairs, Technology, Automotive and Lifestyle, all of which are governed by this Privacy Notice. For an up to date list of these brands please visit [http://www.dennis.co.uk/brands](http://www.dennis.co.uk/brands). 

Below is a non-exhaustive list of our well-known brands: 

Alphr, Auto Express, Bikes Etc, Buy a Car, Carbuyer, Channel Pro, Cloud Pro, Coach, Computer Shopper, Custom PC, Cyclist, Den of Geek, Digital SLR Photography, Expert Reviews, EVO, Fortean Times, Health and Fitness, IT Pro, Know Your Mobile, Men’s Fitness, Octane, PC Pro, The Week, The WeekDay, The Week Junior, Women’s Fitness and Viz.

Dennis Publishing (UK) Ltd includes subsidiary companies Dennis Publishing Ltd, Evo Publications Ltd, The Week Ltd, Octane Media Ltd and Octane (Media) Holdings Ltd, Dennis BuyaCar Ltd, Den of Geek US.

Dennis Publishing (UK) Ltd has formed partnerships with a variety of carefully selected companies. Below is a non-exhaustive list of our key partners: Jellyfish Online Marketing, Google, Lotame, Pubmatic, Sophos3, Convertr, Moat, Integral Ad Science, Taboola, Feefo, Selligent.

### **What information we collect**

To provide you with the best possible customer experience we may ask you to submit personal information such as your name, postcode, email address and phone number. Providing this personal information helps us to provide you with a better experience e.g. showing you content, offers and advertising that may be of more interest to you.   
  
Additionally we use web technologies e.g. cookies and web beacons, to automatically track and log limited personal data and link this with information you or other data suppliers have provided. For detailed information on the Cookies we use please see our Cookies Policy [here](http://www.dennis.co.uk/cookie-policy/).

Anonymous data will be recorded for the purpose of reporting web traffic statistics, advertisement ‘click-throughs’, and/or other activities on our sites.

Furthermore we work with our partners Audience Science, to carry out Online Behavioural Advertising on our websites. Online Behavioural Advertising aims to provide you with more carefully targeted advertising. If you wish to know more about Online Behavioural Advertising or you wish to opt out of Online Behavioural Advertising by Audience Science please go to [http://www.youronlinechoices.com/uk/](http://www.youronlinechoices.com/uk/).

Our iPad, Android and other ‘apps’ may use services provided by Flurry Analytics, Google Analytics or Mixpanel. The purpose of using these providers is to collect user data which we use to learn about our readers and improve the app. 

To find out more, visit [https://policies.yahoo.com/us/en/yahoo/privacy/index.htm](https://policies.yahoo.com/us/en/yahoo/privacy/index.htm). 

In order to opt out of this you need to go to the providers directly. You can do this through the following links:

<https://mixpanel.com/optout/>

**How we use your data**

The personal information we obtain will be used for the following purposes. 

Technical administration of the web site, enhancing your experience of the site, research and development, customer service, marketing, advertising targeting and making your personal data available to selected partners. This will, where you provide your consent, include Dennis and our partners (set out above) sending you information about products and services that may be relevant to you, by email, mobile messaging, postal mail or direct telephone contact. All of the above are subject to your stated preferences; we and our content partners will always make it clear how you can prevent i.e. opt-out of these uses.

We may use third party suppliers to provide part of our service to you. In some circumstances these providers may be based in countries outside the European Economic Area whose laws provide for a different standard of protection for your personal information than that provided under UK Law. In such circumstances we will have in place strict contractual arrangements that will require your information is processed securely, at least to a standard equivalent to the UK Data Protection Act 1998 and where relevant the supplier must be signed up to EU-US Privacy Shield July 2016.

Your personal data will not be disclosed to state institutions and authorities except if required by law or other regulation. Before we release data on this basis, we will ensure that the information is being provided to a genuine and properly authorised investigation. If we are not satisfied that there are valid grounds for releasing the information, the Data Protection Act does not oblige us to do so. If we refuse to release the information, law enforcement agencies may obtain a court order requiring us to provide it.

**Individual Choice**

You can change your personal information preferences and/or details at any time. As a magazine subscriber you can access your preferences by logging on to www.managemymags.co.uk using your Managemymags account ID. You can also unsubscribe to any/all lists by sending an email request to [privacy@dennis.co.uk](mailto:privacy@dennis.co.uk) (including your full name, postcode and magazine subscription / competition information).

You will ALWAYS be given a straightforward way to opt out from our direct marketing each time you receive a communication from us or one of our advertising partners.  
  
****

**Access to Personal Information**

Under the Data Protection Act 1998 you have the right to access your personal information (subject to certain exemptions). If you wish to find out what information, if any, we hold that relates to you, you must make your request in writing. You can help us to process your request by providing us with information that will help us identify records we hold that relate to you. For example your name, address, email address, telephone number, subscriber id. A charge of £10 is made for these requests.

Please send your request along with a cheque for the sum of £10 made out to Dennis Publishing Ltd to The Data Controller, Dennis Publishing (UK) Ltd, 31-32 Alfred Place, London, WC1E 7DP.

**Personal information security**

Dennis Publishing (UK) Ltd security policies, rules and technical measures have been implemented to protect your personal information from unauthorised or improper use and from accidental loss.

All our employees and data processors that have access to, and are associated with, the processing of your personal information are legally obliged to respect the confidentiality of your data and are bound by contract to do so.

Note that some of our websites provide forums and commenting facilities where you can post information. When you do so, be aware that other visitors may collect any information you make public.

**Privacy Support**

If you have an enquiry or concern about our Privacy Notice, please contact: The Data Controller, Dennis Publishing (UK) Ltd, 31-32 Alfred Place, London, WC1E 7DP. If you are not satisfied with our response you may wish to contact the Information Commissioner via their [website](https://ico.org.uk/)

If we decide to change our Privacy Notice we will post these changes on this page so that you are always aware of what information we collect, how we use it and in what circumstances we disclose it. 

In the event of any part of Dennis Publishing (UK) Ltd either being sold or going into receivership, we reserve the right to continue to share your data to third parties in accordance with the latest preferences you have provided. You will be informed should any change of ownership occur, and the new owner will manage your personal information preferences.

**Business Third Party Data**

We occasionally purchase data from third party suppliers. The data we purchase is business data. Business data may include but not be limited to a business email address, business job title, business postal address. Such a purchase may result in you receiving communications from Dennis Publishing regarding your business sector or business interests without your having directly supplied your information to Dennis Publishing. We keep clear records of the data suppliers, if you have any queries concerning the use of business data please email [business-data-privacy@dennis.co.uk](mailto:business-data-privacy@dennis.co.uk).
